(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-12T18:12:52.053934",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
こんねね！
Kon-nene!
ホロライブ5期生お笑い担当、
Hololive 5th Generation's comedy rep,
みんなの心のエネルギー、ドリンク、桃鈴ねねです！
and everyone's emotional energy drink, Momosuzu Nene!
今日はねねの誕生日！
Today is Nene's birthday!
みんなハッピーバースデーありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you all so much for the happy birthdays! Thank you!
えー、というわけで今日は#桃鈴ねね生誕祭2024でたくさんポストしてください！
So today, please post a ton using the #MomosuzuNeneBirthday2024 hashtag!
今日は今からですね、ねねの大好きなゲームで遊んだりとか大好きなみんなと歌ったりとか色々やっていきたいと思います！
So starting right now, I want to do all sorts of things like playing my favorite games and singing with all of you!
というわけでねねたんの大冒険いくぞー！ま、歩いていくか。
With that said, let's begin Nene-tan's grand adventure! Well, let's walk there.
あー、やっと着いたー！マジ疲れた！歩いてくるの本当に。
Ah, I finally made it! I'm so exhausted! Walking all the way here is no joke.
わくわくわくわく入城しちゃうぞー！
I'm so, so excited to enter!
すっごい、おおー！すっごい楽しみ！おおー！これは！このゲームは！
This is amazing, whoa! I'm so excited! Whoa! This is... This game is...
えー！
Whoa!
あれっ？
Huh?
セクシーダンスって言って、あー転んだ！
They said "sexy dance" and—oh, she tripped!
ちょっと、どういうこと？
Wait, what's going on?
というわけで今日はまつりちゃんとはあとにしてもらいました！
So today, we had Matsuri and Haato join us!
そしてはあとも久しぶり！
And Haato, it's been a while!
うん、久しぶりだよ。
Yeah, it's been a while.
二人はラブベリやったことありますか？
Have you two ever played Love and Berry?
まつりはね、あります！
Matsuri has, yes!
おお、あのオシャレ魔女です。
Oh, that Oshare Majo.
おー、服を着るね！服を着るね！
Oh, you get clothes! You get clothes!
え、はあとも？え、本当に初めて？
Eh, and Haato? Eh, really your first time?
本当にはじめて！
Really my first time!
本当に初めて？本当に初めて！
Really your first time? Really my first time!
え、初見です。じゃあまだオシャレ魔女じゃないんだ。
Ah, first-time viewer. So you're not an Oshare Majo yet.
オシャレ魔女じゃない。ま、そういうことになりますね。
Not an Oshare Majo. Well, that's how it is.
じゃあ今日よろしくお願いします。
Well then, looking forward to today.
はい、というわけで今日ははあともオシャレ魔女になってもらおうと思って、早速遊んでいきたいと思います！
So today, we thought we'd have Haato become an Oshare Majo, and let's go play right away!
ラブベリっていうのは、おしゃれを自分でコーディネートして、ダンスリズム、おしゃれバトルみたいなのをするんだよね。
Love and Berry is where you coordinate outfits yourself and do dance rhythm, fashion battle stuff, right?
だからそれをやるにはまずおしゃれ力を上げないといけないんです。
So to do that, you first need to raise your fashion power.
なのでそれを研究するモードがあるので、それで遊んで、その後にあのリズムゲームで遊んでいきたいと思います！
So there's a mode to research that, so we'll play that, and then play with the rhythm game afterwards!
はい！
Yes!
というわけで今回はねねのお披露目のカードを…
So this time, Nene's debut cards...
マジですごいじゃん。これ普通にセットしてあったらやばい。本当にやばい。
This is seriously amazing. If this was normally set up, it'd be crazy. Truly crazy.
これ押したら、始まるらしいんですよ。
They say if you press this, it starts.
ちょっとやっちゃおうよ。いいの？
Let's do it. Is that okay?
カードが出てきたよ！
A card came out!
え、カード出てきた！何がでてきたの？
Eh, a card came out! What came out?
マジカルヘアカラー！お,これめっちゃレアなやつだ！
Magical Hair Color! Oh, this is a super rare one!
え、ここに置くんだ。ここに置くんだ！
Oh, you put it here. You put it here!
で、まずはこのおしゃれけんきゅうモード…
And first, this Fashion Research mode...
けんきゅうって何すんの？
What do you do in research?
その場所に合わせて、基本的にコーディネートするんだよ。
You basically coordinate according to the location.
時間内でコーディネートできるように練習するモード。
A mode to practice so you can coordinate within the time limit.
まずはねねがお手本でやっていくと、ラッキーカラーは青色です！
First, Nene will show an example. The lucky color is blue!
青いドレス、青いドレス！
Blue dress, blue dress!
そっか、ぶとうかいだからね。ドレスね！
Right, it's a ball. A dress!
え、じゃあこれにしよう。ねねのまねしてよ。
Eh, then let's do this. Copy Nene.
ロイヤルターコイズっていうドレス！青だからね！すごい！
A dress called Royal Turquoise! Because it's blue! Amazing!
ロングアップヘアにして…ロングアップヘア！
Make it long up hair... Long up hair!
スキャンすることによって色が変えられるんだ。
By scanning, you can change the color.
あ、下がった！どこで見てんの、下がったって？
Ah, it went down! Where are you looking to see it went down?
あ、左で見てるんだ！
Ah, looking on the left!
マジカルヘアカラー…あ、青がある！
Magical hair color... Ah, there's blue!
すごい！
Amazing!
ジュエリーサンダル…あ、うわ！めちゃくちゃ合ってる！
Jewelry sandals... Ah, wow! It matches so well!
もうセットじゃんこれ！じゃあこれで、ほぼ100%に近いね。
This is already a set! So with this, it's close to almost 100%.
よし！おー！レッツゴー！お！333！すごい！
Yosh! Oh! Let's go! Oh! 333! Amazing!
お、可愛い！
Oh, cute!
や、アイドルステージといえばこの衣装みたいなのがあるよね。
Yeah, when you say Idol Stage, there's this kind of outfit.
めっちゃ行く！めっちゃ行く！ぴったりね！
Going great! Going great! Fits perfectly!
ちょっと海のっぽい感じの、大しおよこむすび！
A slightly ocean-like vibe, Oushio Yokomusubi!
ミラクルヘアカラーの…あ、でも合ってたんだ！すごい！
Miracle hair color... Ah, but it matched! Amazing!
これで1回実際にたいせんしてみよっか。
Let's actually do a battle once with this.
うん、いぇーい！リズムもかかってくるね。
Yeah, yay! The rhythm gets going too.
じゃあ、いくよ！
Alright, here we go!
まちでうわさのラブとベリー
The talk of the town, Love and Berry,
ダンスとおしゃれがだいすき！
they love dancing and fashion!
いつもふたりはプリティ
The two of them are always pretty,
ときめき決めてるチビティ
looking tokimeki-chibi-ty!
でもだいじなことは…
But the important thing is...
みた目じゃない
It's not about looks!
まちでうわさの…
The talk of the town...
やさしくなくちゃ
If you aren't kind,
おしゃれしたって ダメ！ダメ！
looking stylish just won't cut it!
こころに響く リズムが大ジ
The rhythm echoing in your heart is important.
こころに響く ことばが大ジ
The words echoing in your heart are important.
まちでうわさの ラブとベリー 今日もふたりはベリーハッピー
The talk of the town, Love and Berry! Today they are very happy!
あしたはふたりでおかいもの しぶやのわんこがまっている
Tomorrow they'll go shopping, Shibuya's dog is waiting!
フリープレイだよ
It's Free Play!
あ、びっくりしたー！
Ah, you scared me!
え、なんか、今聞こえたと思ったの。
Huh, I thought I just heard something.
ねぇたち、セカイに入っちゃっててさ、いまの。
Hey girls, you guys got sucked into the world just now.
てか、はあちゃんさ、まじで完璧に踊ってたんだけど、すごくない！？
And Haachama, you were dancing totally perfectly, isn't that amazing!?
初見じゃないからさ、練習してきてんだよ！
It's not my first time, I practiced for it!
そっか、練習してきてんだね。
I see, you practiced for it.
すごい、がんばったよね！
That's amazing, you worked hard!
え、じゃあここね、まあ、ちょっと、まじょとしてね、一歩進んできたね、ねたち。
Uhh, so here, well, as witches, you guys took a step forward.
そう、おたりせんで、もう優勝者を決めていきたいと思います！
That's right, without any matches, we'll decide the winner right here!
なるほど！
I see!
マジック対決！
Magic showdown!
ええ、やろやろ！
Yay, let's do it!
そうね。
Right.
はあちゃんと、まつりちゃん。
Haachama and Matsuri.
あ、まつりいく？
Ah, Matsuri, you going?
おっけー。
Okay.
ぶとうかい まつり vs はあと
[Battle: Matsuri vs Haachama]
ピンクだ！急げ！
It's pink! Hurry!
服は、これ、ど定番！
As for clothes, this is the classic!
いきなりきっちょんじゃね？これ。
Isn't this high-class right off the bat?
まつりちゃんぽい？
Does it look like Matsuri?
まつりちゃんぽいかな？
でもベリーの定番、いや、でもラブの定番なんじゃ…あ、そうなんだ。
But Berry's classic—wait, isn't it Love's classic... Ah, is that so.
お姫様ヘア！
Princess hair!
お姫様ヘア。あーもう、定番だね。
Princess hair. Ah, classic.
これはこれだ！
This is it!
あとはファンデーションね。
And then foundation.
確かに、ミラクルファンデーションだ。おめかししないと。
True, Miracle Foundation. Gotta dress up.
オシャレまほう…やばいよ！
Stylish Magic... Oh no!
はあちゃんは緑だよ！緑！緑やさん！
Haachama is green! Green! Green lover!
緑やさん、なんだっけこれ…これだ！
Green lover, what was this... this is it!
そっち、そっち、そっち。
That way, that way.
これだ！これだ！
This! This!
え、ここにDって書いて…あ、これは関係ないのか。ドレスのDだ。
Eh, there's a D written here... Ah, this isn't related? It's D for dress.
グッズ！
Goods!
こっちもやってみなくていいの？
Shouldn't we try this one too?
ほらこのドレスも見てみて。やってみる。
Look, look at this dress too. Let's try it.
この靴とあとこっちのほうが合う気がするけど、色変えられるんだよ！
I feel like these shoes match better, but you can change the colors!
すごい！
Amazing!
じゃあちょっとやってみよう。でもね、もうちぎれないや。
Then let's try it. But you know, we can't rip it anymore.
これやって、でも髪の毛…
Do this, but the hair...
きらりんドレス！これも定番感あるよね。
Kirarin Dress! This also has a classic feel.
お姫様ヘア！
Princess hair!
まだスリッパだよ！まだスリッパだよ！
Still slippers! Still slippers!
スリッパやだ。
I hate slippers.
グリーンドンキーヒール！
Green Tinker Heel!
でもちょっと、これ使って…
But wait, use this...
そうそうこれ！
Yeah, yeah, this!
これ使って、色変えたら？
Use this, and change the color?
そう、おしゃれができたら、ボタンを一緒に…
Right, once you finish styling, press the buttons together...
お！さっき出たカードね！
Oh! The card that came out earlier!
ジュエリーサンダル！ねえ！
Jewelry sandal! Hey!
おお、お、ほら！
Oh, oh, look!
キラキラ！色変えれるよ！
Sparkly! You can change colors!
黄色にしとくのがいい感じ。もうちょっとのびね。
Yellow looks pretty good. A bit more stretch.
ああ、ちょっと、なのにね。
Ah, wait, even so.
もっと、あ、ちょっと低いかも！
More, ah, maybe a bit low!
もう時間が…！あ、時間が決まった！
Time's up...! Ah, time's up!
ラッキーカラー、ここ17！
Lucky color, here 17!
すごい！すごい！
Amazing! Amazing!
ここ17、すごい！すごい！315！
Here 17, amazing! Amazing! 315!
さあ、でもない戦いだね、これ。
Well, this is an uneven battle.
髪型も揃いじゃん。やばい、これもう初めて聞いたこれ。
Even the hairstyles match. Oh no, I'm hearing this for the first time.
やばいやばい！たんだん！
Yaba yaba! Tandan!
たんだん たんだん たんだん…
Tan-dan, tan-dan, tan-dan...
まつりちゃんのまねするわ！
I'll copy Matsuri's style!
たんだん たんだん たんだん…
Tan-dan, tan-dan, tan-dan...
いや、いまのシャケ殺したら、え、ちょっと！あ、でも！
Wait, if we killed that salmon now, eh, wait! Ah, but!
たんだん たんだん たんだん…
Tan-dan, tan-dan, tan-dan...
けっかはっぴょう！まつりの勝ち！
Results announcement! Matsuri wins!
めっちゃおしゃれきんじょう！
Super stylish!
やばい！めっちゃやったからね、このステージ！
Awesome! We played this stage a lot, you know!
よーし、じゃあ次は…
Alright, then next...
やったー！
Yay!
かわいい
Cute!
すぐキタ
It came right away!
えっ？
Huh?
えーっと
Urm...
待って
Wait.
ラッキーだ！
It's lucky!
おしゃれパワー
Oshare Power...
245!
かわいい
Cute!
50!
えっ？
Huh?
おしゃれパワー
Oshare Power...
271!
でもラッキーが周りに
But there's lucky around...
大丈夫、ベリーの
It's fine, Berry's...
あ、ラッキーが２個もある！
Ah, there are two luckies!
やばい、この曲も知らん
Oh no, I don't know this song either!
懐かしい
So nostalgic!
曲が聞こえないんだけど
I can't hear the song!
曲が聞こえない
自分の声で、自分の声で
Over my own voice!
自分の声で曲が
My own voice is...
曲にそれで妨害されるしかないのかも知れない
Maybe I'll be hindered by the song!
ぱ、パジャマ作ってるじゃん！
W-Wait, you're making pyjamas!
パジャマも終わりだ
The pyjama is ending too—
あ、パジャマ終わりじゃん
Ah, the pyjama is ending!
パジャマ終わりじゃん！
The pyjama is ending!
音何にも聞こえなかった
I couldn't hear any sound at all!
じゃあ、最強決めちゃう？最強決めちゃおっか。
So, shall we decide the strongest?
おしゃれが
If fashion is—
できたら、右と左のボタンを
done, press the right and left buttons!
気になった？
Were you curious?
２７５！すごい！
275! Amazing!
２０まるだ
20 circles!
ラッキー２０まるだ
It's a lucky 20 circles!
決まった
Decided!
あ、ラッキー、ラッキーまるだ！
Ah, lucky, lucky circle!
大丈夫はベリーのボーナスステージよ
Daijoubu is Berry's bonus stage!
おお、来た！
Oh, it came!
最初からボーナスステージ
Bonus stage right from the start!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
ラブのポーズだよ
It's Love's pose!
ベリーのポーズだよ
It's Berry's pose!
ラブのポーズだよ
It's Love's pose!
ベリーのポーズだよ
It's Berry's pose!
ラブのポーズだよ
It's Love's pose!
オッケー！
OK!
みんな、すごい！
Everyone is amazing!
ABC de イイ感じじゃない
ABC de - It's not a bad feeling!
1・2・3でジャンプしよう
Let's jump 1, 2, 3!
ABC de everybody is all right
ABC de - Everybody is all right!
1・2・3でレッツゴー！
Let's go, 1, 2, 3!
胸に刺さった想い
Feelings pierced my chest...
ご縁もないくらい
Hardly any connection left.
忘れかけたあの日のこと
Of those days I almost forgot.
ABC de イイ感じじゃない
ABC de - It's not a bad feeling!
1・2・3で踏み出そう
Let's step out 1, 2, 3!
ABC de イケルさ大丈夫
ABC de - We'll be fine!
1・2・3でオッケー！
OK, 1, 2, 3!
ABC de イイ感じじゃない
ABC de - It's not a bad feeling!
1・2・3でジャンプしよう
Let's jump 1, 2, 3!
ABC de everybody is all right
ABC de - Everybody is all right!
1・2・3でレッツゴー！
Let's go, 1, 2, 3!
いやー、お疲れ様！
Man, good work!
お疲れ様、きつかったね、きつかったー！
Good work, that was tough!
じゃあ、おしゃれ魔女ビンゴコー！
Now, Oshare Majo Bingo!
あー、上がってきたー！めっちゃ上空、あ、ちょっとあんまり飛ばないでー！
Ah, we're going up! Don't fly too high!
止まらないで
Don't stop!
落ちちゃう 落ちちゃう！
We're gonna fall, we're gonna fall!
やばい やばい！
Oh no, oh no!
お尻揺れてる お尻揺れてる！
Our butts are shaking, our butts are shaking!
回ってる 回ってる 回ってる！
We're spinning, we're spinning, we're spinning!
待って カブトムシで口付いてんの？
Wait, are we kissing on the beetle?
え？本当だ！
Eh? For real!
ほら、鼻糞付いてるでしょ？
Look, it has a booger on its nose, right?
人間味あふれる鼻糞
A very human-like booger.
キスしちゃおうかな
Should we kiss it?
キスするとさ ついでに食べたくなっちゃうよね
If you kiss it, you'll wanna eat it too, right?
あのね、ちょっと待って。こないだね、やっぱ考えないといけないことはちょっと…
Well, wait a minute. The other day, there's something I gotta think about, but...
ちょっと次のために着替え…
Changing for next time...
空の上！空の上で！
In the sky! Up in the sky!
そう、空の上！
That's right, up in the sky!
これ空の上だと、やっぱみんなが見てるから。
Up here in the sky, everyone's watching us.
ああ、なるほどね。ま、二人は外向いてるけど、私たちを見れてるけど。
Ah, I see. Well, the two of you are facing outside, so you can see us.
ま、いいよ、じゃ、見てもいい。見てほしいんだよね。
Well, it's fine, you can watch. We want you to watch.
見ない、見ない！
We won't look, we won't!
じゃあ見るじゃん！
Then you are looking!
いやー、でも、しょうがないじゃん！
Man, but, it can't be helped!
いや、ノーパン！ノーパンなんだよね、本当は！
No panties! We're actually not wearing any panties!
ねぇ、やばいよね！
Hey, that's crazy!
ほら見て！プリプリ、お尻プリプリ！
Look! Jiggle jiggle, jiggling our butts!
ぷりぷり、涙、ハゲ散らかし！
Jiggle jiggle, tears, going bald!
早着替え、早着替え、早着替え！
Quick change, quick change, quick change!
これね、ネネだけ着替えたのは、ちょっとネネは次のところで、あの、別のことしないといけないから。
The reason only Nene changed here is because Nene has to do something else in the next part.
あ、なるほど！もうすぐ見えてくると思うんだけど。
Ah, I see! I think it'll come into view soon.
ええ、えっとね、あそこ、あそこ！
Um, let's see, over there, over there!
あそこか！
Over there!
あ、下りまーす！
Ah, going down!
降りる！降りる降りる降りる！
Landing! Landing, landing!
じゃあ、ネネはこの森で、
Now, Nene, in this forest,
ムシキングしないといけないの。
needs to play Mushiking.
あ、ムシキングいいな！
Oh, Mushiking is great!
え、そうなの。だから、二人には先にステージで待ってて。
Yeah, so you two go wait on stage first.
オッケー、待ってる。まだあるからね。まって、そうだよ、忘れないでね、休憩しててください。
Okay, we'll wait. There's still more. Wait, yeah, don't forget, take a break.
オッケー！楽しんできてね！楽しんできてね！
Okay! Have fun! Have fun!
いやもう本当、楽しみ。めっちょ楽しみなんだよね。
Man, I'm really looking forward to it. I'm so excited.
じゃあまた後でね！バイバーイ！楽しんで！
See you later then! Bye-bye! Have fun!
がんばってね！バイバーイ！
Do your best! Bye-bye!
はい上がって、はい上がって！行くよー！
Pull yourselves up, pull yourselves up! Let's go!
はい、バイバーイ！
Yep, bye-bye!
こんにちは！ムシキング！
Hello, Mushiking!
こちらも、セガさんに今回貸していただきました！
This was also lent to us by SEGA this time!
ということでね、みんなと一緒に、このリアルでね、このゲームセンターでムシキングをしてる当時の様子を再現したくて、今から生配信でやっていきたいと思います！
And so, we wanted to recreate the feeling of playing Mushiking in a real arcade with everyone, and we'll be playing it live right now!
というわけで、ムシキングをやっていきましょう！というわけで、カードは今回も例のカードを持ってきました！
So, let's play Mushiking! And for the cards, I brought the usual cards this time too!
ストーリーモードがムシキングにあって、アニメとはまたちょっと違う内容でね、やっているので、一緒にルール説明をしながらストーリーモードでちょっと遊んでいきたいと思います！
There's a story mode in Mushiking, which has a slightly different content from the anime, so I'd like to play through story mode while explaining the rules together!
ムシキングはね、ムシカードと、あ、ちょうど出てる。ムシカードとわざカードっていうのがあって、それを組み合わせて相手のムシとじゃんけんで戦うみたいな感じで、勝った方が勝ち。じゃんけんに勝った方が勝ちというゲームです。
Mushiking has beetle cards and, oh, right there. Beetle cards and technique cards, and you combine them to battle opponent beetles in janken, and whoever wins is the winner. It's a game where winning janken means you win.
一応、わざごとにね、相性がったりとかはするんだけど、まぁそれはね、興味を持たれた方はもっともっと調べてみてください。とっても奥が深いです！
There are compatibilities for each technique, but well, if you're interested, please research it more. It's very deep!
え、あ、オラァ！
Eh, ah, take this!
ゲームをえらんでね。あ、最初まずさ、最初の、ひとりで遊ぶこれがいちばん最初のやつじゃん。
Choose a game. Ah, first, the very first one, playing solo, this is the very first one, right?
やばい、音が！音がでかすぎる！
Oh no, the sound! The sound is too loud!
うん、やばい。生まれたばかりのムシを育てるんだ。
Yep, oh no. You raise a newly born beetle.
あ、やばい、興奮しすぎてよだれ出る。
Ah, oh no, I'm getting too excited and drooling.
あ、これ超必殺わざって、相手の超必殺わざチョキだから。
Ah, this super finishing move, the opponent's super finishing move is Choki (Scissors).
カブトムシに出てきて戦うよ！
A beetle will come out and fight!
え、カブトムシに出てきてもらおう！
Uh, let's have a beetle come out!
さあ、ネネが召喚するムシ、おいぜ！
Now, the beetle Nene summons, come on!
よしよしよし、何にしよう！
Alright alright alright, what should we choose?
グーわざを覚えたよ！
Learned a Gu (Rock) technique!
下から通すハサミわざを覚えたよ！
Learned a passing-from-below Hasami (Scissors) technique!
パーわざを覚えたよ！
Learned a Pa (Paper) technique!
さあ、来い！ネネの、ネネのムシ！
Now, come! Nene's, Nene's beetle!
うおおお！やった！
Woohoo! Yay!
エレファスゾウカブト！やばい、生まれたてだからね、まだね、羽の色がちゃんとしてないの。
Elephant beetle! Oh no, since it's just born, its wing color isn't properly set yet.
ネネの、ネネの当時の最強デッキだよ、これ！
This is Nene's, Nene's strongest deck from back then!
すぐに戦います！
Let's fight right away!
頑張って！
Do your best!
相手の超必殺技がちょきだから、
Since the opponent's super special attack is Scissors,
ねねがグーを出せば、もうこれは勝ちってわけよ。
if Nene plays Rock, this is a total win.
やった！
Yay!
ちょっとバランス感がかわいそうすぎる。
Her sense of balance is way too pitiful.
ねねの勝ちですね、これ完全に。ちょっとかわいそう。
Nene wins for sure, this is complete. A bit pitiful.
かっこええー！
So cool!
あ、いい、いい。これ2発で行けるかも。
Oh, nice, nice. Might be able to do this in two hits.
あ、こうやってね、あの主人公の、ポプくんて言うんだけど、ポプくんが
Ah, like this, the protagonist is named Pop-kun, and Pop-kun...
じゃんけんのアシストをしてくれる
...helps you with rock-paper-scissors.
優しい仕様なの。
It's a kind feature.
おお、いけ！
Oh, go!
イエーイ！やった！
Yay! We did it!
2番目の敵
The second opponent.
これみんなゲームの音って知ってる？
Does everyone know this game's sound?
聞こえる？これ虫キングのゲームの音。
Can you hear it? This is Mushiking's game sound.
あ、見て！ちょっと羽が…ちょっと羽が茶色く…あ、気をつけてってことはこれね、チョキでくるの。
Ah, look! The wings are brown... ah, 'watch out' means it's coming with Scissors.
必殺技でするから、ねねはグーでする。
It'll use a special move, so Nene will use Rock.
気をつけてねの時は、相手の得意の技が来るんだよね、大体。
When it says 'watch out', the opponent's signature move usually comes.
このシワリモードとかだと、もうこのポポのアシストでほぼ勝てる。
With this Siwaru mode or whatever, you can almost always win with Popo's assist.
必殺技を食らってフラフラしてる。チャンスだよ！
Hit by a special move and wobbling. It's a chance!
これもう1回出せるってことなんだと思う。
I think that means you can use it one more time.
フラフラしてるから、もう1回必殺技出したら最強だよ！みたいなアシスト来る。
It's wobbling, so if you use your special move again, you're the strongest! That kind of assist comes.
ポポさんまだから。
Popo-san is not yet...
やった！羽がもっと固まったよ。おお！なんか羽がヤバヤバの時に戦うちょっと…
Yay! The wings got even harder. Oh! Fighting when the wings are in trouble...
3番目の敵
The third opponent.
アクティオン？
Actaeon?
まだ赤い目の虫に見つかってしまった！マルスか。
Found by a red-eyed bug! It's Mars.
この赤い目っていうのは、ポポの、敵、森の中の、妖精界の敵みたいなのがいるんだけど、
These red eyes... Popo's enemies, like fairies' enemies in the forest...
その人は、虫を赤い目に改造して、
...that person modifies bugs with red eyes...
無理やり、あ、ここのおじさん、このおじさん！このおじさんに戦わせようとしてるの。
...and forcefully, ah, this old man, this old man! Tries to make this old man fight.
やった！これを倒して、赤い目の、そのアダーコレクションて言うんだけど、赤い目の虫から解放してあげるみたいなのするの。
Yay! Defeat this and release the red-eyed bug from the 'Adder Collection', like that.
解放している意味。マルスゾウカブト、さっさと片付けろ。
The meaning of releasing. Mars Elephant Beetle, tidy up quickly.
さっさと片付けろってことは、必殺技っぽいからね。アース…あ、やばい！
'Tidy up quickly' sounds like a special move. Earth... ah, oh no!
あ、でも、必殺技ではないか。
Ah, but wait, is it not a special move?
これこれ！ドーン！ガキーン、ガキーン、チュリチュリチュリチュリ…
This, this! Boom! Clang, clang, zzz...
はあ、この音、この音。ポポ、もう後がないぞ。
Hah, this sound, this sound. Popo, you have no way out.
え、これはね、必殺技一択だからね。やった！後がないぞって言って必殺技出すしかないぞって今アシストもらってんのさ。
Eh, this is definitely a special move choice. Yay! You're getting an assist saying 'there's no time left, you have to use a special move'.
アダ、の中の、エルファス最強ってわけ。これ、この音！
Elphas is the strongest in Adder. This, this sound!
羽が固まった！
The wings hardened!
最後の敵
The final opponent.
4回戦
Round 4.
完全体になりよ。ブルーマイスターツヤクワガタじゃんこれ。
Become a complete form. This is Blue Meister Stag Beetle.
あ、やばい、超必殺技がマックス設っちゃう。
Ah, no, the super special move is at max setting.
サイズ感的には僕たちの手を呼んでいるよってことは
In terms of size, calling for our hands means...
グーを出そうとして、パーを出そうとするの、チョキ。
...trying to play Rock, trying to play Paper, Scissors.
じゃあローリングクラッチホールド。見たそうだって思ってたんだよ、ずっと。
Then Rolling Clutch Hold. I've been thinking I wanted to see it all along.
きまった！がんばた！
Nailed it! Good job!
ぼくたちの手を呼んでいるよ。
Calling for our hands.
ってことはグーのチョキだから…
That means Rock's Scissors, so...
あ、やばい、巻きちゃう！あ、行くか！
Ah, no, I'm gonna lose! Ah, will it work?
やった！必殺技だ！行くぞ！
Yay! Special move! Let's go!
メキメキメキ…そうなのよ。メキメキメキってやるんだよ。
Crack, crack... That's right. It goes crack, crack, crack.
アダ、もう諦めろ！
Adder, give up already!
わ、これ生んだな。もう諦めるの時は生んだんだけど。
Wow, this produced it. At the time of giving up, it produced it.
あ、やばい、やばい！やばい！
Ah, oh no, oh no! Oh no!
アースエッジ！
Earth Edge!
これね、なんか技カードにも2パターンあって、なんか攻撃する技と、なんか他の技とか、虫へのアシストみたいなのするカードもあるの。
You see, there are two patterns of skill cards: attack skills, and other skills like assisting the bug.
あ、やばい、やばい、やばい、やばい！消された！
Ah, oh no, oh no, oh no, oh no! Erased!
あ、やばい、やばい、やばい！
Ah, oh no, oh no, oh no!
あっ、しまった
Ah, dammit.
あっ、ちょっとエレファス？
Ah, wait, an Elephant beetle?
ダメだよ、つよさが…
No good, the strength is...
あ、やばい、負けちゃった
Ah, crap, I lost.
あっ、これ持ってます
Oh, I have this one.
これね、虫の育成もできるし
You can raise bugs in this too,
次の友達に代わる時はムシキングカードを使わないでね
and when switching friends, don't forget the Mushiking card!
ねがれんぷれいです
Right? Replay!
ゲームをえらんでね
Choose a game.
新しいお話しだよ
It's a new story.
一人であそぶ、改造こうちゅうと戦う
Play alone, fight against modified bugs...
この改造こうちゅうのところのストーリーを見ると
If you look at the story about these modified insects,
そのアダーコレクションのところ分かるんだよ
you'll understand that Adder Collection stuff.
どうやってこの
How did
あのー、このアダーの虫が生まれてきてるかみたいな
um, these Adder bugs come into existence, sort of.
昔はさ、ここ緑色がかわいそうすぎて
Back in the day, the green color was way too pitiful,
ネネの、ネネの虫くん
Nene's, Nene's bug-kun...
何かなー？
I wonder what it'll be?
まあ、でも相手の必殺技パーだからね
Well, but the opponent's special move is Paper, so,
ねねはチョキ勝ち、チョキ勝ちしていきたいところではある
Nene wants to win with Scissors, keep winning with Scissors.
えい！きたー！
Hah! It's here!
ギラファ！ギラファノコギリクワガタ！
Giraffa! Giraffa stag beetle!
おいおいおいおいおいおい
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
そうそうそう
Right, right, right.
ほらほら見て、後ろでさ
Look, look, see, behind us,
最初は必殺技で来るから、パーで、チョキ、パー、チョキ
they'll come with a special move first, so Paper, then Scissors, Paper, Scissors...
やった！必殺技だ！
Yay! Special move!
いいの？ブルロック出ちゃっていいの？
Is that okay? Is it okay to use Bull Lock?
戻さないケース
the case where you don't return it.
あれ？ぽぽのアシストが足りない
Huh? Popo's assist isn't enough.
こうやって改造して無理やり戦わせてんの
Modifying them like this and forcing them to fight...
可哀想すぎな、ブルロックだ！
Too pitiful, it's Bull Lock!
ムシキングカードにはアダーコレクションっていうのもあって、その赤い目をこっち側にして戦うこともできる
Mushiking cards also have Adder Collection versions where you can fight with the red eye facing this way.
ね、ちょっかっこいい
Man, looks pretty cool.
もうさなぎからだいぶ帰っちゃってて時遅しだけどな
They've already changed from chrysalis, so it's a bit too late though.
アルキデス大平たくわがた
Albidus flat stag beetle
もうビチビチなんだから、フレームいっぱいに名前書いてる
They're thrashing around so much, names written across the whole frame.
やばい、もう生まれてんんだよね、見えてる、見えてる
Crap, they're already born, I can see them, I can see them.
ローリングドライバーね！
Rolling Driver!
これね、みんな大好きローリングドライバー
This right here, everyone's favorite Rolling Driver.
まだうまく動けないんだ
They still can't move properly.
当然に
Naturally.
そうよね、でもまだうまく動けない時に
That's right, but when they still can't move properly,
百烈拳いきます！
Here comes Hundred-Fist Strike!
ねぇなんかさ
Hey, like,
姉ちゃんが、姉ちゃんがこの、このデッキで行くわって
Big sis was like, 'I'm going with this, this deck,'
ブラザールに見せたらさ、甘いなって言われた
and when she showed Brazar, he told her she was naive.
だめなんだよね、そういうパワーでゴリ押ししようとしたら、サポートの技入れないとダメだよって言われた
He said it's no good trying to bulldoze with sheer power without putting in support moves.
なんかめちゃくちゃ悔しかったわ
Man, that was super frustrating.
わ、なんておじさんだ
Man, what an old guy.
リッキー！リッキーに時間稼がそうとすんなよ
Ricky! Don't try to buy time for Ricky!
これボーズみんなの憧れなんだから
This is every boy's aspiration,
リッキーとギラファの戦いめちゃ熱くない？手を選んでる
Isn't the battle between Ricky and Giraffa super hot? Choosing hands...
リッキーブルー、さっさと片付けろってことパーだからチョキ
Ricky Blue, meaning finish it quickly, so it's Paper, hence Scissors.
これのためにこの超必殺技合わせしてんだよ。
That's why we're timing these super special moves together.
ムシキングってこういうゲームエキサイトするでしょ？
Mushiking is that kind of game, it gets you excited, right?
おっこれが楽しくて
Oh, this is so fun...
これが楽しくてさ！急ごう！
This is so fun! Let's hurry!
最後にいきつけだったのは…
The one we finally reached was...
いでよ、パラワンオオヒラタクワガタ！お前の力を見せてやれ！
Appear, Palawan giant stag beetle! Show me your power!
いろんな各所を回って全然並んでないところを探す。
Going around to various places to find somewhere without a line at all.
最初はグー、じゃんけんぽん！
First is rock, rock-paper-scissors!
あ、さらに読まれてる。読みが読まれてる！あ、かたづけろ言われた！あ、やばい！
Ah, read again. My move was read! Ah, it told me to clear away! Ah, oh no!
ああ、まずい！
Ah, this is bad!
やばい、ノコギリクワガタとして平らに負けられない！
Oh no, as a saw stag beetle, I can't lose to a flat stag beetle!
うわ、どうしよう？
Wow, what should I do?
もっとヒートアップ！まずいまずい…
Heat up more! Bad, bad...
あぶ！やめて！
Close! Stop!
あっぶねえ！パラワンオオヒラタクワガタ、とどめを刺すのじゃ！
That was close! Palawan giant stag beetle, deliver the finishing blow!
さすがに、さすがに超必殺技強え！
As expected, the super special move is so strong!
あ、まずい！
Ah, bad!
ああー、ねねのギラファ…
Ahh, Nene's Giraffa...
何すんだよ！きみは負けてしまった！
What are you doing! You lost!
勝つの時は、勝ちの時の画面も見ない！
When winning... I won't even look at the winning screen!
甲虫王者ムシキングスーパーコレクション面白いよね！みんなのカードが使えるよ！
Mushiking: King of the Beetles Super Collection is fun! Everyone's cards can be used!
膝が…膝がもう力入れすぎちゃって。
My knees... My knees put in too much strength.
いない、いない、いない、いないわ。
Nobody, nobody, nobody's here.
次のお友達がいるときは大体もうこうやってずっと画面見られてるし、交換できるカードがないかずっと見られてるんだよな。
When the next friend comes, they usually keep watching the screen like this, and checking if there are cards to exchange.
はあー。
Sigh.
えーっと、と、いう、これもう1回やってもいいんだっけ？
Um, wait, can I do this again?
あ、もうできない、時間がないって！
Ah, I can't do it anymore, there's no time!
これ欲しい！ってわけで改めてセガさん、今回は本当にありがとうございましたー！
I want this! So once again, SEGA-san, thank you very much!
え、じゃあ最後にね、まあこの今広い、クソ広い森の中にきていますのでね。
Eh, well lastly, we've come into this wide, damn wide forest.
ねのね、ムシキングの愛、ていうか虫への愛、ムシキングへの愛を、え、歌いたいと思います！
Nene's love for Mushiking, or rather love for bugs, love for Mushiking, I'd like to sing!
ゲーム版ではなくアニメ版のムシキングの曲、聞いてください、「生きてこそ」！
Not the game version, but the anime version of Mushiking's song, please listen to it: "Ikite Koso"!
ママ私が生まれた日の空はどんな色
Mama, what color was the sky on the day I was born?
パパ私が生まれた日の気持ちはどうだった
Papa, how did you feel on the day I was born?
あれから言葉を覚えて私なりの
Since then I have learned words and in my own way
愛も甘え方も身体にしみこんだ
Love and how to be spoiled soaked into my body
生きてこそ、生きてこそ
Because I'm alive, because I'm alive,
今ここから始まる
now from here I will begin.
生きてこそ、生きてこそ
Because I'm alive, because I'm alive,
広がってまたつながる
spreading and connecting again.
ママ私を初めて抱く気持ちはどうだった
Mama, how did it feel to hold me for the first time?
パパ私が生まれた日は嬉しかった
Papa, you were happy on the day I was born.
あれからキセキを重ねて…私なりの
Since then, stacking miracles... in my own way
愛も出会いも育てて生きたい
I want to live, nurturing love and encounters.
生きてこそ、生きてこそ
Because I'm alive, because I'm alive,
無限に羽ばたいていく夢
the dream of flying infinitely takes flight.
生きてこそ、生きてこそ
Because I'm alive, because I'm alive,
その根は深く太く強く
Its roots grow deeply, thickly, and strongly.
生きてこそ、生きてこそ
Because I'm alive, because I'm alive,
生きてこそ
because I'm alive...
ママ私が 生まれた日の 空はどんな色
Mama, what color was the sky on the day I was born?
パパ私が 生まれた日の 気持ちはどうだった?
Papa, how did you feel on the day I was born?
あれから言葉を覚えて 私なりの 愛も甘え方も 身体にしみこんだ
Ever since then, learning words, my own way of loving and depending became ingrained in me.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 今ここから始まる
Living, truly living—now it begins right here.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 広がってまたつながる
Living, truly living—it spreads and connects once more.
ママ私を 初めて抱く 気持ちはどうだった?
Mama, how did you feel holding me for the very first time?
パパ私が 生まれた日は 嬉しかった?
Papa, were you happy on the day I was born?
あれからキセキを重ねて… 私なりの 愛も出会いも 育てて生きたい
Stacking miracles ever since... I want to live and nurture my own loves and encounters.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 無限に羽ばたいていく夢
Living, truly living—a dream soaring infinitely.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ その根は 深く 太く 強く
Living, truly living—its roots are deep, thick, and strong.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 今ここから始まる
Living, truly living—now it begins right here.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 広がってまたつながる
Living, truly living—it spreads and connects once more.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 無限に羽ばたいていく夢
Living, truly living—a dream soaring infinitely.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ その根は 深く 太く 強く
Living, truly living—its roots are deep, thick, and strong.
その根は 深く 太く 強く yeah 羽ばたいて 生きてこそ
Its roots are deep, thick, and strong—yeah, soaring high, truly living...
ママ私が 生まれた日の 空はどんな色
Mama, what color was the sky on the day I was born?
パパ私が 生まれた日の 気持ちはどうだった?
Papa, how did you feel on the day I was born?
あれから言葉を覚えて 私なりの 愛も甘え方も 身体にしみこんだ
Ever since then, learning words, my own way of loving and depending became ingrained in me.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 今ここから始まる
Living, truly living—now it begins right here.
生きてこそ 生きてこそ 広がってまたつながる
Living, truly living—it spreads and connects once more.
ママ私を 初めて抱く 気持ちはどうだった?
Mama, how did you feel holding me for the very first time?
パパ私が 生まれた日は 嬉しかった?
Papa, were you happy on the day I was born?
あれからキセキを重ねて… 私なりの 愛も出会いも 育てて生きたい
Stacking miracles ever since... I want to live and nurture my own loves and encounters.
はい、というわけで、生きてこそ でした！
Yes, and that was "Ikite Koso"!
ねえ見てなんか 森の民たちがさ、こう、ご、ご…まっていく感じが、むっちゃ表現されてるでしょ、このキラキラで！
Hey look, like, the forest folk are gathering in such an expressive way with all this sparkle!
えーというわけで、えー… よっこいしょー！
So anyway, uh... heave-ho!
はい、上がってください！よいしょ！よいしょー！
Alright, come on up! Heave! Ho!
えー、みなさん、今は、えー虫キングの世界にいたんですけど、
Um, everyone, we were just in the world of Mushi King, right?
ま、ねねの大好きな虫、ギラファのクワガタが…
Well, Nene's favorite insect, the giraffe stag beetle...
ヘラクレス今日ちょっと…ちょっと出す、用意はしてたんだけどね、出す機会がなかった、ヘラクレス。
I had Hercules ready to bring out today, but there was just no opportunity, Hercules.
えー、いろんな虫たちへの、ねねの大好きな思いを込めて作った曲が
So, I made a song filled with Nene's deep love for all kinds of bugs,
あるよね？というわけでそれを、え、みんなで歌いたいと思います！
right? So, uh, I'd love for everyone to sing it together!
ステージがね、なんかそのへんにあるんだけど…あ！あそこ！あそこ！
The stage is, like, somewhere over there... Ah! Over there! Over there!
ハッピーギラファ～～！
Happy Giraffa!
ねねちのギラギラファンミーティングへようこそ！
Welcome to Nenechi's Gira Gira Fan Meeting!
さあ！ツノと頬をなで～～く伸ばして
Now! Stretch out your horns and cheeks wide,
思いっきり、楽しんじゃおうね！
and let's enjoy it to the fullest!
それじゃあ、いくよ～～！
Here we go!
アミーオ！ カケーロ！ ビバ！ギラファ！！
Amie o! Kake o! Viva! Giraffa!!
kabu-kuwa ギラギラ最高だね kabu-kuwa amore kabu-kuwa yeah kabu-kuwa
Kabu-kuwa—Gira-gira is the best, kabu-kuwa! Amore kabu-kuwa yeah, kabu-kuwa!
クリクリおめめラブ kabu-kuwa asore kabu-kuwa yeah
Big round eyes full of love, kabu-kuwa! Asore, kabu-kuwa yeah!
愛のダンスはムーチョムーチョ
The dance of love is mucho mucho!
飛んでシュビドバメロメロ
Flying, shubiduba, falling head over heels!
awawa-wawawa
みんな集まれゾロゾロ
Everyone, gather around in a line!
こん chu☆ chu☆
Kon☆ chu☆ chu☆!
パヤパヤパヤパヤ
Paya paya paya paya!
ギラギラ ギラファ ファ ギラギラ ギラファ
Gira-gira giraffa, fa, gira-gira giraffa!
目覚めたら元気におはよう
Wake up and say a cheerful good morning!
お洒落なんてそっちのけで 出かけよう
Forget about dressing up, let's head out!
いってきまーす！
I'm heading out!
エレファス コーカサス ヘラクレス ノコギリ タランドゥス
Elephas, Caucasus, Hercules, Sawtooth, Thalandus!
さあ！ファンミーティングが始まる 出ておいでよ
Now! The fan meeting is beginning, come on out!
アミーオ！ カケーロ！ ビバ！ギラファ！！
Amie o! Kake o! Viva! Giraffa!!
kabu-kuwa ギラギラ最大きゅきゅきゅ kabu-kuwa amore kabu-kuwa yeah kabu-kuwa
Kabu-kuwa—gira-gira to the max, kabu-kuwa! Amore kabu-kuwa yeah, kabu-kuwa!
テカテカツヤツヤの kabu-kuwa asore kabu-kuwa yeah
Shiny and glossy, kabu-kuwa! Asore, kabu-kuwa yeah!
ぱっつん前髪ムーチャムーチャ
Blunt bangs, mucha mucha!
可愛い得樹液をペロペロ
Licking up the sweet tree sap!
awawa-wawawa
みんな集まれゾロゾロ
Everyone, gather around in a line!
こん chu☆ chu☆
Kon☆ chu☆ chu☆!
パヤパヤパヤパヤ
Paya paya paya paya!
皮付きバナナと砂糖と焼酎 たっぷり袋に加えましょう
Banana peels, sugar, and shochu—add plenty into the bag!
両手でクワッと鮟鱇捉え さあ！揉んで揉んで揉んで揉んで
Grab hold with both hands, now! Knead, knead, knead, knead!
発酵させた愛の樹液 i want you 君専用ジューシー
Fermented tree sap of love, I want you, your exclusive juice!
カブクワ欲しけりゃ塗りたくれ！
If you want stag beetles, smear it on!
サッサッ サッサッサ 塗ったら揺らせ
Rub it on, smear it, once coated, shake it!
ユッサッ ユッサッサ 落ちなきゃ叩き
Rock it, sway it, if they don't drop, tap it!
バンバン！ バンバンバン！ 採れなきゃ踊れ
Bang bang, bang bang bang! If you can't catch them, dance!
ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘイ！ ヘーーイ！！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Heeeey!!
すごい！みんなのおかげで、こんなにたくさんのカブクワたちが集まってくれたよーー！！
Amazing! Thanks to everyone, so many stag and rhinoceros beetles have gathered here!!
自分に拍手～！そして、自然に拍手～～～～！
Give yourselves a round of applause! And applause for nature too!
アヌビス レガウス マルマルス ニジイログランディス
Anubis, Legaus, Malmars, Rainbow Grandis!
みんなそれぞれ愛してるけど やっぱり君が好き
I love each and every one of you, but after all, I love you best!
ハッピーギラファ～～！！
Happy Girafa~~!!
ねねちのギラギラファンミーティングへようこそ！
Welcome to Nenechi's Giragira Fan Meeting!
ツノと頬をなか～～く伸ばして
Stretch out your horns and cheeks nice and long!
おもいっきり 楽しんじゃおうね
And let's enjoy ourselves to the fullest!
それじゃあ いいくよ～～！
Here we go~~!
アミーを！カケーーロ！
Cast the Amiee!
ビバ！ギラファ！
Viva! Girafa!
kabu-kuwa
ギラギラ最高だね kabu-kuwa
Kabu-kuwa, peak sparkle!
kabu-kuwa
クリクリおめめラブ kabu-kuwa
Big round lovey-dovey kabu-kuwa!
愛のダンスはモーチオモーチオ
The dance of love is mo-chio mo-chio!
飛んでシブドゥボメロメロ
Flying and melting away, shibu-dubo melo-melo!
みんな集まれゾロゾロ
Everyone gather around, zoro-zoro!
こん＾～chu☆ chu☆
Kon^~ chu☆ chu☆!
目覚めたら元気におはよ
Wake up and say good morning energetically!
お洒落なんてそっちのけ出かけよう
Forget about fashion and let's head out!
「行ってきまーーす！」
"We're heading out!"
エレファス コカソサ ヘラクレス
Elephantis, Caucasus, Heracles!
ノコギリタランドゥス
Nokogiri, Tarantus!
さあ！ファンミーティングが始まる
Now, the fan meeting begins!
アミーを！カケーーロ！
Cast the Amie!
ビバ！ギラファ！
Viva! Girafa!
kabu-kuwa
ギラギラ最大きゅきゅ kabu-kuwa
Maximum sparkle kabu-kuwa!
皮付きバナナと砂糖と焼酎
Banana with peel, sugar, and shochu,
たっぷり袋に加えましょう
let's add plenty into the bag!
両手でクワッと鷲掴み
Grab it firmly with both hands!
揉んで揉んで揉んで揉んで
(Knead, knead, knead, knead!)
発酵させた愛の樹液
Fermented sap of love,
i want you君専用ジェリー
I want you, your exclusive jelly!
カブクワ欲しいけりゃ塗りたくれ！
If you want kabu-kuwa, slap it on!
サッさっさっさっさ
Rub, rub, rub, rub!
ユッサッユッサッさ
Shake, shake, shake!
パンパン！パンパンパン！
Bam, bam, bam bam bam!
パンパン！台パンパン！採れなきゃ踊れ
Slam! Table slam, dance if you can't catch 'em!
すごい！みんなのおかげで こんなにたくさんのカブクワが集まったよ！
Amazing! Thanks to everyone, so many kabu-kuwa have gathered here!
自分に拍手！そして自然に拍手を！
Give yourselves a round of applause! And a natural applause!
アヌビスレギウス丸丸丸
Anubis, Regius, Maru Maru Maru,
ニジイロクラニジツ
Rainbow Stag, Cladognathus!
みんなそれぞれ愛してるけど やっぱり君が好き
I love everyone in their own way, but I still love you best!
ギラギラギラギラ
Sparkling, glittering!
強くてカッコ良い
Strong and cool!
ギラギラファンタスティックなノコギリは宝物よ
A sparkling, fantastic sawstag is my treasure!
アミーを！カケーーロ！
Cast the Amie!
ビバ！ギラファ！
Viva! Girafa!
カブクワ
Kabu-kuwa!
ギラギラ最高だね カブクワ
Kabu-kuwa, peak sparkle!
カブクワ アモーレ カブクワ イエー！
Kabu-kuwa, amore kabu-kuwa yeah!
カブクワ カブクワ ヘイ！
Kabu-kuwa! Kabu-kuwa! Hey!
クリクリおめめラブ カブクワ
Big round lovey-dovey kabu-kuwa!
カブクワ アモーレ カブクワ イエー！
Kabu-kuwa, amore kabu-kuwa yeah!
カブクワ カブクワ ヘイ！
Kabu-kuwa! Kabu-kuwa! Hey!
カブクワ カブクワ カブクワ...
Kabu-kuwa! Kabu-kuwa! Kabu-kuwa!
カブクワ ヘイ！
Kabu-kuwa! Hey!
こん＾～chu☆ パパパパパ
Kon^~ chu☆ Papapapapa!
あたたたたたたたたたたたずっきゅん！
Atatatatatatatata Zukkyun!
わたたたたたたたたたたたどっきゅん！
Watatatatatatatata Dokkyun!
づっきゅん！どっきゅん！づっきゅん！どっきゅん！
Zukkyun! Dokkyun! Zukkyun! Dokkyun!
ヤダ！ヤダ！ヤダ！ヤダ！never! never! never!
No! No! No! No! Never! Never! Never!
C!I!O! チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！いいかな？
C-I-O! Chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, is that okay?
でもね ちょっとweight ちょっと最近心配なんです
But you know, a bit of weight, I've been worried lately.
だけど チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！いいかな？
But chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, is that okay?
でもね ちょっとwait ちょっと待って チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！
But hey, just a bit of wait, just wait, choco-choco-choco!
あたたたたたたたたたたたずっきゅん！
Atatatatatatatata Zukkyun!
わたたたたたたたたたたたどっきゅん！
Watatatatatatatata Dokkyun!
づっきゅん！どっきゅん！づっきゅん！どっきゅん！
Zukkyun! Dokkyun! Zukkyun! Dokkyun!
マダ！マダ！マダ！マダ！never! never! never!
Still! Still! Still! Still! Never! Never! Never!
C!I!O! チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！いいよね？
C-I-O! Chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, isn't that good?
でもね ちょっとweight ちょっと最近心配なんです
But you know, a bit of weight, I've been worried lately.
だけど チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！いいよね？
But chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, isn't that good?
でもね ちょっとwait ちょっと待って チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！
But hey, just a bit of wait, just wait, choco-choco-choco!
too too late! too too late!
too too p! p! p! come on!
Too, too P-P-P (Please, please, please) come on!
あたたたたたたたたたたたずっきゅん！
Atatatatatatatata Zukkyun!
わたたたたたたたたたたたどっきゅん！
Watatatatatatatata Dokkyun!
づっきゅん！どっきゅん！づっきゅん！どっきゅん！
Zukkyun! Dokkyun! Zukkyun! Dokkyun!
ヤダ！ヤダ！ヤダ！ヤダ！never! never! never!
No! No! No! No! Never! Never! Never!
ヤバい 超！超！ハード 超！イッパイ頑張ったんです
It's crazy, super, super hard, I worked super hard!
だから ちょっとハート ちょっとだけお願いなんです
So just a little heart, I'm just asking for a tiny favor!
早く チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！ちょうだい
Hurry up, chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, give it to me!
よこせ チョコレート チョコレート チョコレート プリーズ！
Hand it over, chocolate, chocolate, chocolate, please!
C!I!O! チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！いいでしょ？
C-I-O! Chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, wouldn't that be fine?
だよね 超！超！good 超！ハッピーで頑張っちゃうんです
Right? Super, super good, working hard while super happy!
だから チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！いいでしょ？
So chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, wouldn't that be fine?
だよね ちょっとだけ ちょっとだけ食べちゃおう！
Right? Just a little bit, just a little bit, let's eat it!
too too late! too too late!
too too p! p! p! come on!
Too, too P-P-P (Please, please, please) come on!
あたたたたたたたたたたたずっきゅん！
Atatatatatatatata Zukkyun!
わたたたたたたたたたたたどっきゅん！
Watatatatatatatata Dokkyun!
づっきゅん！どっきゅん！づっきゅん！どっきゅん！
Zukkyun! Dokkyun! Zukkyun! Dokkyun!
ヤダ！ヤダ！ヤダ！ヤダ！never! never! never!
No! No! No! No! Never! Never! Never!
C!I!O! チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！いいかな？
C-I-O! Chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, is that okay?
でもね ちょっとweight ちょっと最近心配なんです
But you know, a bit of weight, I've been worried lately.
だけど チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！いいかな？
But chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, is that okay?
でもね ちょっとwait ちょっと待って チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！
But hey, just a bit of wait, just wait, choco-choco-choco!
あたたたたたたたたたたたずっきゅん！
Atatatatatatatata Zukkyun!
わたたたたたたたたたたたどっきゅん！
Watatatatatatatata Dokkyun!
づっきゅん！どっきゅん！づっきゅん！どっきゅん！
Zukkyun! Dokkyun! Zukkyun! Dokkyun!
マダ！マダ！マダ！マダ！never! never! never!
Still! Still! Still! Still! Never! Never! Never!
C!I!O! チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！いいよね？
C-I-O! Chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, isn't that good?
でもね ちょっとweight ちょっと最近心配なんです
But you know, a bit of weight, I've been worried lately.
だけど チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！いいよね？
But chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, isn't that good?
でもね ちょっとwait ちょっと待って チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！
But hey, just a bit of wait, just wait, choco-choco-choco!
too too late! too too late!
too too p! p! p! come on!
Too, too P-P-P (Please, please, please) come on!
あたたたたたたたたたたたずっきゅん！
Atatatatatatatata Zukkyun!
わたたたたたたたたたたたどっきゅん！
Watatatatatatatata Dokkyun!
づっきゅん！どっきゅん！づっきゅん！どっきゅん！
Zukkyun! Dokkyun! Zukkyun! Dokkyun!
ヤダ！ヤダ！ヤダ！ヤダ！never! never! never!
No! No! No! No! Never! Never! Never!
ヤバい 超！超！ハード 超！イッパイ頑張ったんです
It's crazy, super, super hard, I worked super hard!
だから ちょっとハート ちょっとだけお願いなんです
So just a little heart, I'm just asking for a tiny favor!
早く チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！ちょうだい
Hurry up, chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, give it to me!
よこせ チョコレート チョコレート チョコレート プリーズ！
Hand it over, chocolate, chocolate, chocolate, please!
C!I!O! チョコレート チョコレート チョコ！チョコ！チョコ！いいでしょ？
C-I-O! Chocolate, chocolate, choco-choco-choco, wouldn't that be fine?
だよね 超！超！good 超！ハッピーで頑張っちゃうんです
Right? Super, super good, working hard while super happy!
だから チョコレート…
So chocolate, chocolate...
はっぴー新年 そろそろ考えなくちゃ
Happy New Year, we need to think about this soon!
みんながちょっとうるさいし まずは作戦会議
Everyone's a bit noisy, first let's have a strategy meeting.
おっけー元年 今からはじまるラブストーリーとか、
Oh hey, New Year! Starting from today is the love story or...
そんなんじゃないし 本命なんだし
No way, it's not like that, it's my true feeling!
今日が本番なんてうそくそ
Today is the real deal? No way, no way!
片思いちょっとハートちょういっぱい 頑張ったんです
I've been trying my absolute best with unrequited love!
だからちょっとハートちょっとだけ お願いなんです
So just a little, just a little is all I ask!
早くチョコレートとチョコレート ちょーちょーちょーだい
Hurry up, chocolate and chocolate, give it to me!
ようこそチョコレートとチョコレート ちょーちょーちょーだい
Welcome, chocolate and chocolate, give it to me!
ちぇけらチョコレートとチョコレート ちょーちょーちょーいいでしょ
Check it out, chocolate and chocolate, isn't that nice?
だよねチョコレートぐっと超ハッピーで頑張っちゃうんです
Right? Chocolate, doing my best and super happy!
だからチョコレートとチョコレート ちょーちょーちょーいいでしょ
So chocolate and chocolate, isn't that nice?
だよねちょっとだけちょっとだけ 食べちゃお
Right? Just a little, just a little, let's eat it!
つーつーれーい とぅーつーれーい
Too, too late! Too, too late!
とぅとぅぴぴぴ かもん
To, to, B, B, B, Come on!
はっぴー新年 そろそろ考えなくちゃ
Happy New Year, we need to think about this soon!
みんながちょっとうるさいし まずは作戦会議
Everyone's a bit noisy, first let's have a strategy meeting.
おっけー元年 今からはじまるラブストーリーとか、
Oh hey, New Year! Starting from today is the love story or...
そんなんじゃないし 本命なんだし
No way, it's not like that, it's my true feeling!
今日が本番なんてうそくそ
Today is the real deal? No way, no way!
えー ピックアップのポーズしてみたいと思います
Let's try a pickup pose!
はーい！ １、２、 まずは私たちから！
One, two, three, first from us!
もうやったじゃん！ ダメじゃん！
Oh, we already did it, didn't we?
ぴーぴーぴーぴーぴーぴー
Pee, pee, pee, pee, pee!
お前！お前！お前！ これ！これ！ 俺が取る！
Hey, hey, hey! What's this? I'm taking it!
隠れてる！ けけけけけけけけけけ
It's hidden! Ke, ke, ke, ke, ke, ke, ke, ke!
ボトル！ボトル！ボトル！ボトル！ けけけけ びー！
Bottle! Bottle! Bottle! Bottle! Ke, ke, ke, B!
びーびーびーびーびーびー
B, B, B, B, B, B!
がんばれびー！
Do your best, B!
できなくない！？
Can you even do this?
はーい！というわけで、私たちピックアップでしたー！
Hi! So, we did the pickup list!
やったー！やったー！やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!
みんなギミチョコ！一話に作ってくれてありがとうございます！
Everyone, Happy Chocolate, thank you for making it together!
めっちゃ作ったよね！めっちゃ作ったよ！
We made it, right? We made it!
というわけで、ねねはまだあるんで、頑張って！
So, Nene still has more, so do your best!
みんな！片付けて！片付けてー！
Everyone, clean up! Clean up!
体育の時間だよー！片付け！片付け！片付け！片付け！片付け！
Let's go to PE class! Clean up, clean up, clean up, clean up, clean up!
行くよ！行くよ！行くよ！
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much.
次に行きます！
Let's move on to the next part.
はーい。
Right.
あのー、大変盛り上がっているとこ恐縮なのですが、
Um, I'm very excited,
ねねからお知らせをさせていただきたいと思います！
I want to make an announcement from Nene!
お知らせこちらでーす！どんっ！
The announcement is right here, ta-da!
お誕生日を記念したグッズが発売されます！イェーイ！
The birthday commemoration goods have been released! Yay!
もう見て丸わかりのとおり、西沢5センセーに描き下ろしてもらいました！
As you can clearly see, Nishizawa 5-sensei drew them for us!
今回は、まあ、お風呂とか？お風呂上がりとか、そういう感じのイメージで、あの、コンセプトで作っております。
This time, like, bath-ish, after-bath-ish kind of image concept,
紹介していきます！まずはこちら！
I will introduce them, first is this!
西沢ママンが描き下ろしてくれたお寿司、B2のタペストリーです！
It's the sushi Nishizawa-sensei drew, B2 tapestry!
なんかこうお風呂上がりにね、ちょっと飲み物なんか飲んじゃって、あぱぱ、あぱぷふってしてる感じのね、ねねのB2のタペストリー！
It's like, after a bath, drinking some drinks, ah-pah-pah, ah-pah-puf feeling.
これ絶対に、絶対に大きいので、絶対にサイズ感が大きいので、
It's definitely, definitely big, definitely the size feeling is big,
皆さんぜひ手に入れてください！
so please everyone get it!
そして次がこちら！
And next is this!
缶バッチです！
Can badges!
最近ね、あの、痛バッグとか作ってくれる人が、あの、X見てて多くて、
Lately, like, I saw many people making ita-bags,
缶バッチもっと増えたらいいなと思って、缶バッチにしました！
I thought it would be good if there were more can badges, so I made it can badges.
イラストはいつもかわいい、あの、ファンアート描いてくれてる、やまねこセンセーに描いていただきました！
The illustration is drawn by the always cute Yamaneco-sensei!
ありがとー！え、そして、続きましてはこちら！
Thank you! And, continuing, we have this!
ビールジョッキ！ま、ビールジョッキって書いてあるんだけど、
Beer mug! Well, it says beer mug,
お風呂上がりにプハッとね、あの、いっぱい飲み物をいただけちゃう、え、ビールジョッキが出ます！
you can drink lots of drinks after a bath, puh-ha!
ねねの配信でご飯時な時が多いので、
Since there are many times when Nene has dinner on stream,
これでみんなで一緒にご飯時にプハッとしましょう！
let's all do "puh-ha!" together at dinner time with this!
そして、なんかお風呂っぽいの1個欲しいなと思ってこちら！
And, I thought it would be nice to have something bath-like, so here!
サウナホルダー！
Sauna holder!
なんかあの、お風呂行ったときに、外のお風呂に行ったときに、あの鍵かけるときに
Like, when you go to the bath, when you go to the outside bath,
使うやつ、あの鍵のやつで、
using that, the key thing,
女はこれで頭を結び上がりますね、これで。
you can tie your hair up with this!
これまとめ上がりまして、
This ties it up together,
あの、鍵をなくさないのと同時に髪をまとめ上がります、これで。
so you can tie your hair at the same time as not losing the key!
え、で、それのキーホルダー、なんかちょっとお風呂っぽい感じのねねが描いてあって、
And its key holder has a cute bath-like Nene drawn on it,
色はね、猫の色にしてあります！
and the color is cat's color!
そして次はこちら！
And next is this!
ボイス、シチュエーションボイス「ねねのお風呂ボイス」！
Voice, situation voice "Nene-chi's Bath Voice"!
というわけでね、一緒にいっしょに入ってるか入ってないかは、みんなの耳で確かめてください！
So please check with your own ears whether you're in it together or not!
そして今回も、え、フルセットの購入特典がありまーす！
And this time too, there are purchase benefits for the full set!
フルセットを購入していただきますと、
If you purchase the full set,
ポストカードと特製のボイスがついてきます。
it comes with a postcard and a special voice track.
購入特典はね、見てみんな、あの、お顔がね、ちょっともう酔っ払っちゃっぴ、
The purchase bonus—everyone look, her face is a bit... totally plastered, hic—
みたいなお顔になってるポストカードと、え、直筆サイン＆、
a postcard with her looking totally tipsy, and a handwritten signature &
複製メッセージ入りポストカード！そして、お風呂上がりにいっぱい喉が渇いて飲んじゃって、あー酔っ払いっちゃっちゃみたいなボイスがついてきます。
a postcard with a replicated congratulatory message! And a voice track like: "Ah, I got so thirsty after a bath and drank too much, I'm totally tipsy, hic—!"
ボイスがついてきます。
is included.
ぜひぜひぜひぜひ、あの、よろしくお願いします。ありがとうございます！
Um, please check it out. Thank you very much!
そしてですね、今回、あの、本当はね、ねぽラボ全員呼びたかったんですけど、
And also, this time, actually I wanted to invite all of NePoLaBo,
ま、タイミングとかね、ちょっと体調のこともありまして、
but due to timing and health reasons,
ラミィが来れなかったんですよ。
Lamy couldn't make it.
でも、う、ラミィ、なんか、なんかちょうだいて言ったら、あの、お便りをくれたので、ラミィのお便りね、まだ見てないので、
But when I said, "Lamy, give me something!" she gave me a letter, so I haven't read Lamy's letter yet,
あの、ここでさらしていきたいと思います。
and I'd like to read it out right here.
Happy Birthday!
いつも周りの人を笑顔に、そして元気をくれるねねちゃん大好きだよ。
Nene-chan, you always make everyone around you smile and give us energy. I love you!
ポンコツなところもアイドルに全力なところも全部大好きちゅきゅきゅ！
I love everything about you, even your clumsy side and how hard you work as an idol, love-love-love!
ま、これ二人で歌った、歌ってみたの時のやつですね。
Well, this is from when we sang a cover together.
うん、うん、ラミィさん、いい曲、なんかいいじゃないの、なんか。
Lamy-san, isn't this a great song? Kind of nice, you know.
これはちょっと、後で現像して額に入れることにします。
I think I'll get this printed out and put it in a frame later.
というわけで、今日はタイミング的に、え、ラミィはいなくて、そして、おうまろはね、今日、あの、無事に戻ってきたということで、
Anyway, today timing-wise Lamy isn't here, and Omaru has safely returned today, so
お祝いも込めて、え、最後は、え、今回は、えっと、ねぽぽ、え、3人で歌って、いきたいと思います！
to celebrate that, lastly, this time, NePoPo, the three of us will sing it!
それでは最後、Let's go! いいよ！
And now for the final song, Let's go! Here we go!
キミがいないとなにもできないよ
Without you, I can't do anything,
キミのごはんが食べたいよ
I want to eat your cooking.
もしキミが帰ってきたらとびきりの笑顔で抱きつくよ
If you come back, I'll hug you with a huge smile.
キミがいないと謝れないよ
Without you, I can't apologize,
キミの声が聞きたいよ
I want to hear your voice.
キミの笑顔が見れれば それだけでいいんだよ
If I can see your smile, that's all I need.
キミがそばにいるだけでいつも勇気をもらってた
Just having you by my side always gave me courage.
いつまでも一緒にいたいよ
I want to be together forever.
この気持ちを伝えたいよ
I want to express this feeling.
晴れの日にも雨の日もキミはそばにいてくれた
On sunny days and rainy days, you were by my side.
目を閉じればキミの笑顔輝いてる
When I close my eyes, your smile shines.
キミがいないとなにもわからないよ
Without you, I don't understand anything,
砂糖としょうゆはどこだっけ?
where are the sugar and soy sauce?
もしキミが帰ってきたらびっくりさせようと思ったのに
If you come back, I thought I'd surprise you,
キミについつい甘えちゃうよ
I always end up relying on you.
キミが優しすぎるから
Because you're too kind,
キミにもらってばかりでなにもあげられてないよ
I only receive from you and haven't given anything back.
キミがそばにいることを当たり前だと思っていたこんな日々がずっとずっと続くんだと思っていた
I took having you by my side for granted, thinking these days would last forever.
ごめん 今日は気づいたよ
I'm sorry, I just realized today.
当たり前じゃないことに
It's not something to take for granted.
まずはキミに伝えなくちゃ "ありがとう"を
First, I have to tell you "Thank you".
キミがいないと
Without you
何もできないよ
I can't do anything.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとう 届いてるかー！
Thank you! Can you hear us?!
聞こえてますかー！
Can you hear us?!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ちゃんと元気でやってまーす！
We're doing great and full of energy!
キミの胸に 届くから
It will reach your heart,
今は 自信ないけれど
Though I'm not confident right now.
笑わないで どうか聴いて
Please don't laugh, just listen.
想いを 歌に込めたから
Because I put my feelings into this song.
ありったけの ありがとうを
With all the gratitude I have,
二人 のせて 届けたい
I want to put it in a song and send it to you.
この気持ちは ずっとずっと 忘れないよ
I will never, ever forget this feeling.
想いよ 届け
Feelings, reach them.
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
フー！フー！フー！
Woo! Woo! Woo!
ジャージャー！ジャージャー！
Jya-jya! Jya-jya!